Cristiano de Oliveira Faustino

cristiadu@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Cristiano, 24 years old, born in Brazil, and currently living near the Campinas area in São Paulo. I would say I am a Computer Science enthusiastic; I like to work with various aspects of technology, especially if it involves lines of code and logical reasoning. I'm always open to learn new things, and face new challenges. Currently I'm working for Daitan Group as a Software Test Specialist, learning the testing process for VOIP equipment, working with SIP, MGCP, and Megaco protocols.

EXPERIENCE

Daitan Group

01 / 2016 - Currently

Software Test Specialist

Testing Optical Network Terminals (ONT) of a major fiber equipment provider in the US. Currently testing Voip interaction between the equipment, following a Test plan, and looking all the interaction of network packets during a call. Protocols being used and tested include SIP, MGCP, H.248, among others.

Daitan Group 06 / 2015 - 12 / 2015

Intern

6-month internship with opportunity of becoming a full-time employee. Working fixing bugs, and helping on the development of small websites for clients of the project that I am working on. I worked with Java, AngularJS, Javascript, CSS and HTML. The project had as main subject Video and Audio conferences.

Telaeris Inc. 06 / 2014 - 03 / 2014

Software Development Intern

Conception of the SMS-Access system: Along with the embedded system - used for gate authentication through RFID cards - called XPressFreedom (also provided by Telaeris), the SMS-Access web system allows users to use their cellphone to access electronic gates, providing them an alternative way to enter those gates when they lost, or forgot their card.

The system also has a web-administration interface that allows admins to change user's and gate's data, allowing a more abroad control of the whole system.

UFSCar - Federal University of São Carlos

01 / 2012 - 01 / 2013

Intern

Programming of the human resources system (built with java), and the new academic system of the university, using the EJB technology, and the Hibernate and JSF frameworks.

Digicomm Inteligent Systems

11 / 2010 - 03 / 2011

Jr Programmer

Programming of new PHP modules to the ERP and CRM systems created by the company for administrative and support control of a virtual store. It was developed a new version of the ERP system using new technologies like Zend Framework and EXT JS. It was also built the integration with the Ikeda and Magento virtual stores systems.

Alpphoria Criação de Sites, Publicidade e Eventos

01 / 2010 - 11 / 2010

Trainee Programmer

Testing of PHP functions created by the junior and senior programmers, supporting of what was already in use, and development of new PHP functions for the system of ForMedical - a company who sells and distributes medical equipment, located in Campinas, São Paulo.

EDUCATION

Universidade Federal de São Carlos	2011 - 2015
Bachelor's degree, Computer Science	
University of California, San Diego Exchange Student, Computer Science	2014 - 2014
Colégio Técnico de Limeira - Unicamp Technical Degree, Informatics	2007 – 2009
ROJECTS	
Institutional Repository, Development of a DSpace prototype.	06 / 2013 - 12 / 2013

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Institutional Repository, Development of a DSpace prototype.
Universidade Federal de São Carlos

Lost in Translation

06 / 2013 - 12 / 2013

01 / 2014 - 04 / 2014

University of California, San Diego

LANGUAGES • Portuguese (Native or bilingual proficiency) • English (Full professional proficiency)